This is an autonomous robotics demonstration for
Ros two using my solution towards the
assessment. First locate where
we have downloaded the submission files which
contain our source code. First you
want to extract the folder,
within this zip file, unzipping the file
you will find four items. The first bing readme.txt
,which contains all the information
needed to set up the environment.
Making it ready to use and test our package
on the assessment.
Going back we have the src folder
containing the program files for our solution.
You will need to copy this src folder
into a new workspace folder.
Let's call the workspace 'solution'.
And within this folder
paste the src folder.
It will have the package folders
and source code required inside.
Now opening
up a terminal.
Let's navigate into the solutions folder
and check that our src is there.
Good. Then we use Colcon Build to
build the packages, and this should take only a
couple
of moments.
And just check that that has created
the build, install and log folders containing
everything to
run our packages.
Next we need to source
install/local_setup.bash
This allows us to call our
our program packages in ROS2.
Then clear the screen for easier use (optional)
Check that Ros two is running
in this terminal. Yep it is.
And then Ros two launch
solution and then launch the solution.
Using the launch file
solution_nav_launch.py
You can also set the number of
robots here though defaults to one.
By typing num_robots := and the
number you can set it between one, two and
three. For the purpose of this demo, we
will be using two robots with our
package: the solution
towards the assessment.
And we will
let that run.
Skipping ahead a little bit.
So after it's all loaded up.
Here are our two robots already in motion,
heading towards items for retrieval.
So they have detected items in
the environment and are heading towards them.
So we have robot one on the
left and robot two on the right.
Let's look at robot one, you can
see it is picking up an item, and it is
just coming to the end
of where it's determined path.
Reaching its goal, and it should then
set a position back in the home zone to
immediately navigate down towards. This happens as soon
as a robot is holding an item and
has reached any goal,
and is constantly checked.
Now let's look at robot two.
Robot two is nearing the goal position.
on a green item.
And due to longer distances, there can be
little inaccuracies in location of items
Not getting close enough to retrieve.
However, as it's right there
it ends up searching because no items can be fully seen
And by nature, it will run into it
as it navigates to a new position due to turning.
It just means it's delayed home by
a position.
Meanwhile robot one has reached the
home goal, we can now see it turning
around, ready to navigate to more items. And
it has identified some red items and it is
heading there now, whereas robot two has
reached that randomised point and is now closer
to home, and to now realises it is
holding an item and will navigate directly down to
drop this off. Meanwhile, Robot one
has now picked up another red item.
And has immediately decided that
it needs to go home.
Robot two has now reached home and
dropped off the item, allowing it to respawn.
This has all happened within 25 seconds
of simulation time to 4min real-time
A little slow due to computational limitations,
but shows an effective autonomous system. Thank you.